<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure | తెలుగు</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/te/tags/azure/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/te/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Azure</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>te</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Azure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/te/tags/azure/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choroid thickness and CVI Calculation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/te/project/choroid-thickness-and-cvi-calculation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/te/project/choroid-thickness-and-cvi-calculation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;commercial-choroid-segmentation-from-research-to-clinical-reality&#34;&gt;Commercial Choroid Segmentation: From Research to Clinical Reality&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey of developing a comprehensive choroidal analysis platform began with a vision: to bridge the gap between advanced research and real-world clinical needs. Our team set out to create a solution that would not only push the boundaries of AI-powered image analysis but also deliver tangible value to clinicians and patients worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our collaboration with Heidelberg Engineering GmbH, the global leader in OCT imaging technology, was a pivotal moment. Together, we integrated our platform seamlessly into the HEYEX app ecosystem, making sophisticated choroidal imaging analysis accessible to clinicians across the globe. This partnership was more than a technical integration—it was a shared commitment to transforming ophthalmic diagnostics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the heart of our platform lies a suite of advanced AI algorithms, meticulously engineered to deliver precise choroidal thickness measurements and detailed CVI (Choroidal Vascularity Index) mapping. We designed the system to automate what was once a labor-intensive process, reducing analysis time from hours to mere minutes. Clinicians now benefit from standardized, reproducible measurements, enabling consistent patient care regardless of operator or facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technology&#34;&gt;Technology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technical innovation behind this platform is rooted in a hybrid training methodology. By combining ground truth annotations with pseudo-labeling techniques, we maximized the utility of available data while maintaining rigorous accuracy standards. Our robust approach ensures that the system generalizes well across diverse patient populations, a critical requirement for clinical deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key differentiator of our solution is the advanced binarization pipeline. We implemented and optimized state-of-the-art algorithms—Phansalkar, Niblack, and Sauvola—each tailored for specific vessel detection challenges. By systematically combining these techniques, our platform excels at extracting both choriocapillaries and large vessels, providing a comprehensive view of the choroidal vasculature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;impact&#34;&gt;Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vessel analysis architecture employs multi-scale detection and hierarchical segmentation, enabling simultaneous analysis of capillaries and larger vessels. This, coupled with automated choroidal thickness mapping using the widely adopted ETDRS grid, empowers clinicians to monitor changes over time and correlate findings with various retinal and choroidal pathologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deployment&#34;&gt;Deployment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineering excellence was a guiding principle throughout the project. We built an end-to-end solution—from image acquisition to clinical reporting—that is scalable, robust, and optimized for real-time performance. Our team worked closely with Heidelberg’s platform engineers to ensure seamless integration, robust API development, and compliance with stringent data security standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bringing this platform to market required not only technical expertise but also business acumen. Navigating the complexities of commercial collaboration, regulatory compliance, and global deployment, we transformed a research concept into a production-ready, clinically validated product now serving ophthalmology practices worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, the success of this project paves the way for future innovations in AI-driven ophthalmic analysis. It stands as a testament to the power of academic-industry collaboration and the impact that thoughtful, well-engineered technology can have on clinical practice. Our journey from research to commercial reality continues to inspire us to push boundaries and redefine what’s possible in medical imaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This project demonstrates the successful transition from research innovation to commercial reality, showcasing expertise in advanced AI development, clinical application design, and industry partnership management.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
